Richard Wilkosz

Software Engineer

Phone

715-370-8005

Email

richard.w.wilkosz@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/richard-wilkosz-026b4715a

GitHub

github.com/richardwilkosz

Website

richardwilkosz.com

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End	Familiarity
JavaScript	
ES6 / TypeScript	
Vue.js	
Angular	
JQuery	
REST API integration	
HTML / CSS	
SCSS / SASS	
Bootstrap	
Back End	
C# .NET	
Python	
SQL	
Cloud / BaaS	
UX Design	
Responsive design	
Accessibility design	
Wireframing	
Usability testing	
Project Management	

SAMPLE PROJECT

Jira / Confluence

Agile / Scrum Unit testing

Git

Check out **Ray**, a database of movies I own on Blu-ray. It features Vue.js, REST API consumption, and responsive design: richardwilkosz.com/ray

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience writing production-level code. Specializes in user-centered front end development, but delivers clean and reusable full-stack code. Has demonstrated leadership and communication skills by serving as team Scrum Master and mentoring 7 interns over the past year.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Apr 2021 – Present Software Engineer
Sentry Insurance

- Designs and implements web application to replace vendor system with millions of data rows. Back end features C# / SQL batch processes with over 70% test coverage. Front end features MVC design and CRUD data tables. Mentored 2 interns on project.
- Mentors 5 interns for the 2021 summer program. Meets weekly to address technical and company-related questions. Coordinates social events and guest speakers to foster connections.

Jan 2020-Mar 2021

Software Developer

Sentry Insurance

- Digitized the company's 2020 United Way donation campaign with a C# web application, processing nearly 4500 transactions.
- Delivered employee health information system, replacing a 5-page PeopleSoft component with a C# web application.
- Designed and implemented new front end components for 4 legacy systems, including systems owned by other teams.
- Served as team Scrum Master for over 1 year. Led daily meetings, tracked development progress, and communicated milestones and course corrections to management.

May 2018– Dec 2019

Associate Software Developer (Internship)

Sentry Insurance

- Created functional Angular prototype of an administration page for call flow automation. Conducted 3 user interviews to inform the design and presented it to the userbase of department executives.
- Delivered C# web application to replace legacy mainframe system, featuring C# / SQL batch processes and CRUD data tables.

Oct 2017-Dec 2019

Technology Tutor, Writing Tutor

University of Wisconsin-Stevens Point

- Tutored 50+ peers in Computer Science courses: Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, and more.
- Tutored 30+ peers in written communication, including business proposals and technical documents.

EDUCATION

Dec 2019

B.S. Computer Information Systems

University of Wisconsin-Stevens Point

- Double majored in Web Development.
- Graduated summa cum laude.